Many companies were offering this course by doing
BFSI, then I did
not trust it, I thought that maybe they will take money and then they will
not get it done, after that I
saw an advertisement of PW, then I thought that if it is
PW then it is trustworthy, I can trust, so have you got a
job somewhere recently, yes,
in GCSE Lombard as a role Associate Development
Manager, I am saying that if
you have done anything in graduation, have you learnt anything, you are
from science, you are from commerce, but to
go into the industry you need a smart move
and what is that smart move, you did not take a platform
identification,
hi Sania, hi sir, how are you, I am
fine, how are you, I am very fine
and thank you very much, thank you very much for taking out
your precious time here with us
today, you invited me so that
I too get a chance to come here, any time, any
time, so tell me something about yourself, Sania,
my name is Sania Bharti, in the family there is
mom, dad, my younger sister,
we are, dad is a driver and mom
is a housewife, so what have you done in your studies,
San, I have done graduation,
B.Sc in Science, yes B.Sc when
You completed it in 2024, okay, you just
completed class 4, and where are you from,
Bihar, Patna, and from there you
completed your studies, yes, from there, near your home,
yes sir, nice, so something about you, I mean, you had
some goal of taking admission in B.Sc, some dream,
you wanted to become something, you had science in 12th, so you had to
take science in graduation, it became
optional, that you have to take it,
after that you came to Patna
for preparation, then I thought, let's
try in banking, then I did some research about it,
many
companies were offering this course,
doing BFSI, well, while doing research, you
saw some courses about BFSI, okay,
then I did not trust it, I thought, I don't know, they will take
money, then they will get it done or not,
after that I
saw an advertisement for PW, then I thought, no, if PW is
trustworthy, there is trust, yes, then I thought, no, there
is trust here, so something good will definitely come from here, so let's
join, okay, I
mean, I joined in the name of PW, but
before that, I saw something, I mean, what is the course, what will happen through it
Learn how many days the course is, did you
research everything, I didn't do much research, I
just joined it because of the name of the course, I
spoke to the counselor,
he
explained a little bit that it's a three-month course, then
you will get a permanent job
in the banking sector, in the finance sector, so
you can start your career somewhere, right, so
after doing a B.Sc. and coming
directly from a science background to a finance background is
not very easy because
if I look at you, you have studied B.Sc.,
it is completely related to science, and
coming into the finance banking industry, so I
think that's why you thought that to enter this industry, you should
enroll in this course,
yes, you felt that it requires some skills,
some knowledge about it, which was
not there, okay, absolutely correct, so
what knowledge did you acquire in three months, there was a ma'am
who used to take core banking classes
and sir
prepared me a lot especially for the interview and he did this
for confidence,
he also worked very hard for skills, along with
us, so your mentors also worked very hard for us  It was
very nice that you
learnt a lot of skills from them, we were very attached
too, the second batch, the third batch, we were
more attached to them in the first batch, nice, nice, so it is a
good thing that you are
connected as a student and with the teachers, if you are
attached then you
can feel free to ask as a friend if you have any problem, and the gurus
always guide you properly, right, the
three months course is complete,
then how was your journey
after the course, you are struggling well but you have to
work harder on yourself so that you can get a better post, so
obviously you have got a job somewhere,
yes, in GCSC Lombard as a
role Associate Development Manager, that's it, thank
you sir, so where is it, it is in your city itself, it is at
my location itself, it is in Patna itself, it is
in Patna itself, so you are lucky, it means
not everyone gets this opportunity, actually
not everyone gets it at their location, there are
many students from our batch who
shifted to Bangalore or Mumbai, right, right, right,
see, shifting is when you start
No, when I started my career,
I also shifted my job
because there was no option, right, it is not like
that I can go within 2 km from home
and get a job, that is a struggle,
everyone does it, the starting phase is of your
life and at that time you should only focus on
learning things like what is the
industry, how does it work, what
skills are required, now you have entered the industry,
now you have to sustain it in the future too, there is a
lot of competition there too, how to work well,
how to get promotion, so the
focus should be on that, remember that this is my
suggestion, this is my advice that today's youth
think that things should be done very simply, if things were
simple then everyone would do it, right,
then what are you doing,
right, so work on yourself and
when you develop yourself slowly, gradually, it
gives you very good benefits in the long term, yes sir, right, okay, so
you have got a job in ICICI,
ICICI Lombard, right, so tell me one thing, have you got a
job, is there any such course
or  Two skills which you think you had three
months ago, it could be anything, I
mean it could be any skill which you did
not have a month ago due to which
you cracked the job, I
mean speaking in front of a large number of people, there are
10 people here,
so I used to be a bit agitated as to how to speak,
where to start, if I had something in my mind,
it used to remain in my mind, so that does not happen now,
now whatever is in my mind comes out, I have gained
confidence, hesitation is over, I have gained confidence to
speak, I have gained
confidence that yes, you can speak, right, right, right, good, good to know this
and
tell me that if you are from a science background, then
obviously when you went for the interview, the
interviewer must have
asked you some questions, so did those questions which
you learnt in your course, soft
skills are a part of the course, whatever you learnt related to core
banking, whatever domain related
things did it help
you, I mean, whatever was taught, something or the other was
asked from all of them  That yes he could tell and
in the job role he had specifically asked
what is your role and how will you work,
tell me how will you work in the role for which you have come, will you
fit in it, nice, nice, so
sir had already
told us that this is
your role, you have to work on it like this, so it was
sent after informing us about everything, it is
not like that it was sent by hiding, so it
means you
got support from the beginning till the end and yes sir there was support, there was
full support, it was nice, nice, so I will just say
congratulations Sanya and all the
best, you have climbed each and every step, you still have a
long way to go, learn, work hard, it will take a lot of
hard work, you have to learn a lot of things,
as a fresher you are just
starting your career, so I am 100% sure
that you will do very well, okay, all the best
to you and thank you so much for coming here, do
you want to give such a message to the youth
or the children who are not able to do well, they are
not able to understand where to go, what to do  You are
lost, you should keep working on your skills.
If you have skills,
you will get a good job anywhere. And you should never be
disappointed that this is not happening, that is not happening. It might be happening, it will get
better gradually. Yes, keep working on yourself. You should keep
working on yourself. So
smartly, like you did, you
found a platform, found PW skills, did a
BFSI course, and today you
have a job. It is important to have that knowledge for any sector, so
you will have to gain it from somewhere.
Absolutely upskilling is very important. Guys, trust
me, I say
that whatever you have done in graduation, whatever you have
learned, whether you are from science or commerce,
but to enter this industry, you
need a smart move. And what is that smart move? You did
not take a platform identification. And that gap is filled
when you come out after three, four, six months,
like a polished child,
even the interviewer, after seeing you, says that man,
you know a lot and he
selects you in the first interview. So, you are
absolutely right.  Sania and all the very
best once again and thank you so much
for coming thank you sir and inviting me